Register of the Eric Hoffer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Newspaper Columns, 1967-1970
  - "Reflections," nationally syndicated column
    - "Who Needs Freedom?,", 1968 July 7 (Box-folder 95: 31)
    - "Where Do They Go from Here?,", 1968 July 14 (Box-folder 95: 32)
    - "The Pain of Imitating,", 1968 July 21 (Box-folder 95: 33)
    - "The Cult of Violence,", 1968 July 28 (Box-folder 96: 1)
    - "Education and Democracy,", 1968 August 4 (Box-folder 96: 2)
    - "Thoughts on Czechoslovakia,", 1968 August 11 (Box-folder 96: 3)
    - "Forty Years in the Desert,", 1968 August 18 (Box-folder 96: 4)
    - "The Practical Sense,", 1968 August 25 (Box-folder 96: 5)
    - "Common People in America,", 1968 September 1 (Box-folder 96: 6)
    - "A Nation of Lower Mujicks,", 1968 September 8 (Box-folder 96: 7)
    - "Negro Pride,", 1968 September 15 (Box-folder 96: 8)
    - "Can the Middle Fight Back?,", 1968 September 22 (Box-folder 96: 9)
    - "Predictability: Past and Present,", 1968 September 29 (Box-folder 96: 10)
    - "Heaven and the Jailkeeper,", 1968 October 6 (Box-folder 96: 11)
    - "Misfits and Outcasts,", 1968 October 13 (Box-folder 96: 12)
    - "Grievance and Protest,", 1968 October 20 (Box-folder 96: 13)
    - "Man's Most Useful Occupation,", 1968 October 27 (Box-folder 96: 14)
    - "The Stupid, Corrupt Americans,", 1968 November 3 (Box-folder 96: 15)
    - "Avant-Garde,", 1968 November 10 (Box-folder 96: 16)
    - "Negro Anti-Semitism,", 1968 November 17 (Box-folder 96: 17)
    - "The New Empire: A United Europe,", 1968 November 24 (Box-folder 96: 18)
    - "The Cure of Lawlessness,", 1968 December 1 (Box-folder 96: 19)
    - "The ‘Useless' Intellectual,", 1968 December 8 (Box-folder 96: 20)
    - "Thoughts on Affluence,", 1968 December 15 (Box-folder 96: 21)
    - "Who Is Sick?,", 1968 December 22 (Box-folder 96: 22)
    - "Clichés about America,", 1968 December 29 (Box-folder 96: 23)
    - "Decade of the Young,", 1969 January 6 (Box-folder 96: 24)
    - "A New Monster,", 1969 January 12 (Box-folder 96: 25)
    - "An Ill Wind for Israel,", 1969 January 19 (Box-folder 96: 26)
    - "Order on the Campus,", 1969 January 26 (Box-folder 96: 27)
    - "The Birth of Negro Communities,", 1969 February 2 (Box-folder 96: 28)
    - "The Astronauts,", 1969 February 9 (Box-folder 96: 29)
    - "Who the ‘Intellectual' Is,", 1969 February 16 (Box-folder 96: 30)
    - "Who Is Influencing Whom?,", 1969 February 23 (Box-folder 96: 31)
    - "Skills and Freedom,", 1969 March 2 (Box-folder 96: 32)
    - "Our Natural Allies,", 1969 March 9 (Box-folder 96: 33)
    - "The Alibi of Discrimination,", 1969 March 16 (Box-folder 96: 34)
    - "Originating and Borrowing,", 1969 March 23 (Box-folder 96: 35)
    - "Student Activists,", 1969 March 30 (Box-folder 96: 36)
    - "The Quality of a Society,", 1969 April 6 (Box-folder 96: 37)
    - "When Words Are Dangerous,", 1969 April 13 (Box-folder 96: 38)
    - "Israel among the Nations,", 1969 April 20 (Box-folder 96: 39)
    - "Maintenance,", 1969 April 27 (Box-folder 96: 40)
    - "The Weak Things of the World,", 1969 May 4 (Box-folder 96: 41)
    - "Writers and Artists,", 1969 May 11 (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - "Fighting Words,", 1969 May 18 (Box-folder 97: 2)
    - "Guilt and Social Order,", 1969 May 25 (Box-folder 97: 3)
    - "Reflections on the Young,", 1969 June 1 (Box-folder 97: 4)
    - "The Meek Majority,", 1969 June 8 (Box-folder 97: 5)
    - "The Vulnerable Social Body,", 1969 June 15 (Box-folder 97: 6)
    - "What Kind of Country?,", 1969 June 22 (Box-folder 97: 7)
    - "More on the Young,", 1969 June 29 (Box-folder 97: 8)
    - "What Ails Professor Marcuse?,", 1969 July 6 (Box-folder 97: 9)
    - "Past and Future Evils,", 1969 July 13 (Box-folder 97: 10)
    - "Black Pride,", 1969 July 20 (Box-folder 97: 11)
    - "Rudeness,", 1969 July 27 (Box-folder 97: 12)
    - "Sociologists and Violence,", 1969 August 3 (Box-folder 97: 13)
    - "Human Perfection,", 1969 August 10 (Box-folder 97: 14)
    - "On the Campus,", 1969 August 17 (Box-folder 97: 15)
    - "God and the Machine Age,", 1969 August 24 (Box-folder 97: 16)
    - "Change,", 1969 August 31 (Box-folder 97: 17)
    - "Man and God,", 1969 September 7 (Box-folder 97: 18)
    - "Power in America,", 1969 September 14 (Box-folder 97: 19)
    - "The Return of the Past,", 1969 September 21 (Box-folder 97: 20)
    - "The Passage from Boyhood to Manhood,", 1969 September 28 (Box-folder 97: 21)
    - "The Masses and History,", 1969 October 5 (Box-folder 97: 22)
    - "Majorities and Minorities,", 1969 October 12 (Box-folder 97: 23)
    - "Who Has Talent?,", 1969 October 19 (Box-folder 97: 24)
    - "Man and Nature,", 1969 October 26 (Box-folder 97: 25)
    - "Intellectual Refugees,", 1969 November 2 (Box-folder 97: 26)
    - "Holy Revolution,", 1969 November 9 (Box-folder 97: 27)
    - "The Trader in History,", 1969 November 16 (Box-folder 97: 28)
    - "Cities: Past and Present,", 1969 November 23 (Box-folder 97: 29)
    - "In Time of Rapid Change,", 1969 November 30 (Box-folder 97: 30)
    - "Dehumanization,", 1969 December 7 (Box-folder 97: 31)
    - "Civilization in Asia,", 1969 December 14 (Box-folder 97: 32)
    - "Who Makes History?,", 1969 December 21 (Box-folder 97: 33)
    - "Black Power,", 1969 December 28 (Box-folder 97: 34)
    - "In Praise of Luxuries,", 1970 January 4 (Box-folder 97: 35)
    - "The Perils of Affluence,", 1970 January 11 (Box-folder 97: 36)
    - "Israel Stands Alone,", 1970 January 18 (Box-folder 97: 37)
    - "Things Which Are Not,", 1970 January 25 (Box-folder 97: 38)
    - "Who Does Whose Work?,", 1970 February 1 (Box-folder 97: 39)
    - "A Workingman's Country,", 1970 February 8 (Box-folder 97: 40)
    - "The New Type of Rich,", 1970 February 15 (Box-folder 97: 41)
    - "Are Revolutions Revolutionary?,", 1970 March 1 (Box-folder 97: 42)
    - "The Effects of the Negro Revolution,", 1970 March 15 (Box-folder 97: 43)
    - Letters to Eric Hoffer from readers of "Reflections"
      - 1968 (Box-folder 98: 1-2)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 98: 3)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 98: 4)
- National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence File, 1968-1970
  Correspondence, memoranda, working materials, statements, and reports, arranged chronologically by physical form.
  - Correspondence relating to Eric Hoffer's tenure as a commissioner
    - 1968 (Box-folder 99: 1-3)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 99: 5)
  - Memoranda
    - 1968 (Box-folder 99: 6)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 100: 1)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 100: 2-4)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 101: 1-4)
  - Working materials, 1968-1969 (Boxes 102-107)
    Clippings, consultant reports, research reports, and other printed matter
  - Investigative reports, 1969
    - Rights in Concord (Box-folder 108: 1)
    - Rights in Conflict (Box-folder 108: 2)
    - Shoot-out in Cleveland (Box-folder 108: 3)
    - Shut It Down! A College in Crisis (Box-folder 108: 4)
  - Task force reports, 1968-1969
    - Preliminary drafts, 1968-1969 (Boxes 109-115)
      Typescripts
    - Final versions, 1969
      - Assassination and Political Violence (Box-folder 116: 1)
      - Crimes of Violence (Box-folder 116: 2-4)
      - Firearms and Violence in American Life (Box-folder 116: 5)
      - Law and Order Reconsidered (Box-folder 117: 1)
      - Mass Media and Violence (Box-folder 117: 2)
      - The Politics of Protest (Box-folder 117: 3)
      - Violence and the Media (Box-folder 117: 4)
      - Violence in America (Box-folder 117: 5-6)
  - Official statements, 1969
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 118: 1)
    - Printed copies (Box-folder 118: 2-3)
  - Progress report, 1968-1969
    - Typescript drafts, 1968 (Box-folder 118: 4-5)
    - Printed copy, 1969 (Box-folder 118: 6)
  - Final report, 1969 (Box-folder 119: 1-4)
- San Francisco Art Commission File, 1968-1973
  Certificates; correspondence, memoranda, and reports; and minutes, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 120: 1)
    Correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to Eric Hoffer's tenure as commissioner.
  - Certificates of appointment
    - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 120: 2)
    - 1970-1973 (Box-folder 120: 3)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - 1968 (Box-folder 120: 4)
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 120: 5)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 120: 6)
- Lili Fabilli Osborne Correspondence File, 1961-1994
  Letters and cards, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. For correspondence with Eric Hoffer, see CORRESPONDENCE series.
  - General
    - Birthday and Christmas cards (Box-folder 121: 1)
    - Cards of condolence (Box-folder 121: 2)
    - A-Z (Box-folder 121: 3)
  - Bay, Christian and Juanita, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 121: 4)
  - Bethell, Tom, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 121: 5)
  - Brown, Barney, 1994 (Box-folder 121: 6)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1983 (Box-folder 121: 7)
  - Cereghino, Ed, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 121: 8)
  - Cole, Stacy, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 121: 9)
  - Dagani, Nahum and Sarah, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 121: 10)
  - D'Amboise, Jacques, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 121: 11)
  - Dreher, Fred, 1967-1983 (Box-folder 121: 12)
  - Eaton, William and Joan, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 121: 13)
  - Fabilli, Josephine (sister of Lili Fabilli Osborne), 1969-1986 (Box-folder 121: 14)
  - Ferguson, Charles W., 1967-1971 (Box-folder 121: 15)
  - Fitzgerald, Ed, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 121: 16)
  - Gordon, Mitch and Marilyn, 1967 (Box-folder 121: 17)
  - Groot, Monique de, 1961 (Box-folder 121: 18)
  - HarperCollins Publishers (Pamela Jelley, Corona Machemer, Marilyn Small), 1978-1992 (Box-folder 121: 19)
  - Hindraker, Birk, undated (Box-folder 121: 20)
  - Holdren, Dick, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 121: 21)
  - Jones, G. Lewis, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 121: 22)
  - Kittrell, Charlie M., 1981-1984 (Box-folder 122: 1)
  - Klussman, Frieda, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 122: 2)
  - Knight, George and Dora, 1966-1983 (Box-folder 122: 3)
  - Koerner, James D., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 122: 4)
  - Kuettner, Al, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 122: 5)
  - Lawrence, Elizabeth, 1970 (Box-folder 122: 6)
  - Ledger Syndicate (John W. Higgins), 1967-1971 (Box-folder 122: 7)
  - Levy, Jack, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 122: 8)
  - Loeb, William, 1979 (Box-folder 122: 9)
  - McGreevy, John, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 122: 10)
  - Menninger, W. Walter, 1972 (Box-folder 122: 11)
  - Osborne, Eric (son of Lili Fabilli Osborne), undated (Box-folder 122: 12)
  - Phillips, Pauline (pseudonym, Abigail Van Buren), 1969-1974 (Box-folder 122: 13)
  - Quinlan, Wayne and Betty, 1968 (Box-folder 122: 14)
  - Revilla, Toni, undated (Box-folder 122: 15)
  - Roberts, Erling and Muriel, 1971 (Box-folder 122: 16)
  - Roberts, Malcolm and Cindy, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 122: 17)
  - Rowand, E. C. and Mary Louise, Jr., 1968-1984 (Box-folder 122: 18)
  - Sand, Gina and Mort, 1983 (Box-folder 122: 19)
  - Scalapino, Robert and Dee, 1976 (Box-folder 122: 20)
  - Schwartz, Robert L., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 122: 21)
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 122: 22)
  - Straub, Jeff and Alberta, 1979 (Box-folder 122: 23)
  - Straub, Pat and Robert, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 122: 24)
  - Thompson, Edgar T., 1967-1975 (Box-folder 122: 25)
  - Tomkins, Calvin, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 122: 26)
  - Troxell, John, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 122: 27)
  - Wadleigh, Alice, 1964-1976 (Box-folder 122: 28)
  - Wadleigh, Frank, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 122: 29)
  - Wessling, Herb, 1971-1992 (Box-folder 122: 30)
  - Wiggins, Anne, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 122: 31)
  - Wilmer, Harry, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 122: 32)
  - Yates, Margaret, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 122: 33)
- Card File, undated
  Note cards, unsorted and sorted alphabetically by name of author or subject.
  - Unsorted (Boxes 123-125)
  - Sorted
    Consists mainly of quotations, listed by author.
    - A - E (Box 126)
    - F - L (Box 127)
    - M - R (Box 128)
    - S - Z (Box 129)
- Writings by Others, 1950-1973
  - Aikin, Charles (Box-folder 130: 1)
  - Alinsky, Saul D (Box-folder 130: 2)
  - Bay, Christian (Box-folder 130: 3)
  - Bendix, Reinhard (Box-folder 130: 4-6)
  - Brennan, James F (Box-folder 130: 7)
  - Bunzel, John H (Box-folder 130: 8)
  - Cox, Allan J (Box-folder 130: 9)
  - D'Azevedo, Warren L (Box-folder 130: 10)
  - Eastman, Joe (Box-folder 130: 11)
  - Erikson, Erik H (Box-folder 130: 12)
  - Feuer, Lewis (Box-folder 130: 13)
  - Frame, Donald M (Box-folder 130: 14)
  - Groot, Adrian D. de (Box-folder 130: 15)
  - Gutman, Herbert (Box-folder 130: 16)
  - Harte, Carol (Box-folder 131: 1)
  - Hayes, Richard A (Box-folder 131: 2)
  - Jacobson, Norman (Box-folder 131: 3)
  - Kuttner, Robert E (Box-folder 131: 4)
  - Lockley, Lawrence (Box-folder 131: 5)
  - Lund, S. E. Torsten (Box-folder 131: 6)
  - Lynn, David B (Box-folder 131: 7)
  - Lynn, Ralph (Box-folder 131: 8)
  - Malia, Martin E (Box-folder 131: 9)
  - Milgram, Stanley (Box-folder 131: 10)
  - Miller, D. LeRoy (Box-folder 131: 11)
  - Mudrick, Marvin (Box-folder 131: 12)
  - Paine, Thomas O (Box-folder 131: 13)
  - Pitkin, Hanna (Box-folder 131: 14)
  - Rokeach, Milton (Box-folder 131: 15)
  - Roos, Hildegard von (Box-folder 131: 16)
  - Saheboz-Zamani, M. H (Box-folder 131: 17)
  - Schaar, John H (Box-folder 131: 18)
  - Shuman, R. Baird (Box-folder 131: 19)
  - Silverman, Saul Norman (Box-folder 132: 1)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr (Box-folder 132: 2)
  - Stanfield, Reuel (Box-folder 132: 3)
  - Stanley, David (Box-folder 132: 4)
  - Takane, Masaaki (Box-folder 132: 5)
  - Thompson, Wayne E (Box-folder 132: 6)
  - Tyrmand, Leopold (Box-folder 132: 7)
  - Viereck, Peter (Box-folder 132: 8)
  - Wiggins, Anne (Box-folder 132: 9)
  - Wildavsky, Aaron (Box-folder 132: 10)
  - Wright, Guy (Box-folder 132: 11)
- Subject File, 1960-1979
  Brochures, clippings, and serial issues, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Alaska (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - Arab-Israeli War, 1967 (Box-folder 133: 2)
  - Authors League of America (Box-folder 133: 3)
  - Everson, William (pseudonym, Brother Antoninus) (Box-folder 133: 4)
  - Free Speech Movement, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 133: 5)
  - Guevara, Ernesto "Che" (Box-folder 133: 6)
  - Hickel, Walter J (Box-folder 133: 7)
  - Hildebrand, Joel (Box-folder 133: 8)
  - Humphrey, Hubert (Box-folder 133: 9)
    Includes materials relating to the 1968 presidential campaign.
  - Jensen, Arthur Robert (Box-folder 133: 10)
  - Kennedy, Edward M (Box-folder 133: 11)
  - Kennedy, John F (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - Osborne, Lili Fabilli (Box-folder 134: 2)
    See also: LILI FABILLI OSBORNE CORRESPONDENCE FILE
  - Phillips Petroleum Co (Box-folder 134: 3)
  - Student movements, 1968 (Box-folder 134: 4)
  - Wilson, Bryan (Box-folder 134: 5)
- Printed Matter, 1949-1982 (Boxes 135-141)
  Brochures, monographs, reports, and serial issues, largely relating to domestic and international politics, social policy, and education.
- CLOSED (Box 142)
- Sound Recordings, 1969-1981
  Sound tape reels and sound cassettes, arranged chronologically.
  - Sound tape reels
    - One sound tape reel of a talk by Eric Hoffer, 1969 May 9 (Box-folder 143: 1)
    - One sound tape reel of a television interview with Eric Hoffer, 1969 January 28 (Box-folder 143: 2)
  - Sound cassettes
    - One sound cassette of a conversation with Eric Hoffer, undated (Box-folder 143: 3)
    - One sound cassette of a speech by Eric Hoffer, Boston University, undated (Box-folder 143: 4)
    - Three sound cassettes of a speech by Eric Hoffer, "Architects and Nature: On the Primacy of Man,", undated (Box-folder 143: 5-7)
    - Four sound cassettes of a commencement address and talks by Eric Hoffer, Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May 30 (Box-folder 143: 8)
    - One sound cassette of a speech by Eric Hoffer upon receiving the Human Resources Award, Human Resources Congress, Chicago, 1972 August 26 (Box-folder 143: 9)
    - One sound cassette of a speech by Eric Hoffer, College High School, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 143: 10)
    - One sound cassette of a speech by Eric Hoffer, Sooner High School, Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1978 October(?) (Box-folder 143: 11)
    - One sound cassette of an interview with Eric Hoffer, San Francisco, 1980 (Box-folder 143: 12)
    - Two sound cassettes of a talk by William Fredlund, 1981 March 7 (Box-folder 143: 13-14)
- Videotapes, 1963-1979
  Arranged chronologically.
  - "Conversations with Eric Hoffer," 12 VHS videotape cassettes, 1963 (Box-folder 144: 1-12)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0005890
    Interview by James Day of KQED. 12 parts.
  - "Eric Hoffer: The Passionate State of Mind," television interview with Eric Sevareid, 1967 September 19 (Box-folder 145: 1)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0006312
    CBS News special. Commercials breaks are included in recording. Recording is from the CBS News Archive.
  - "The Savage Heart: A Conversation with Eric Hoffer," television interview with Eric Sevareid, CBS, 1969 January 28 (Box-folder 145: 2)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0006318
  - "People of Our Time: Eric Hoffer," John McGreevy Productions, 1974(?) (Box-folder 145: 3-4)
  - Reflections from the Waterfront, with Eric Hoffer, 1974 (Box 145)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0008548
    Program on Eric Hoffer
  - "Eric Hoffer at Woolaroc," Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1977 April(?) (Box-folder 146: 1)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0002065
    Director: S. Clark. Outdoor interview of Eric Hoffer conducted by Judy Hagedorn (sp?) and Jan Kazier (sp?). Color, unedited footage. Produced by Oklahoma Educational Television Authority (OETA).
  - "An Evening with Eric Hoffer: Capitalism," Bartlesville, Oklahoma, parts 1-2, 1977 April (Box-folder 146: 2-3)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0002064
    Eric Hoffer lecture "Capitalism" given in Bartlesville, Oklahoma. Introduction by Charlie Kittrell of Philips Petroleum Co. Produced, directed by Jim Rankin. Produced by Oklahoma Educational Television Authority (OETA).
  - "Eric Hoffer: Points of View and Positions in Life," Bartlesville, Oklahoma, parts 1-3, 1979 July (Box-folder 146: 4-6)
    Use copy reference number: 94057_v_0002062
    Studio interview of Eric Hoffer conducted by Charlie Kittrell of Philips Petroleum Co. Bartlesville, OK. Produced by Oklahoma Educational Television Authority (OETA).
- Photographs, 1950-1985
  Prints, albums, and oversize prints, arranged by physical form and chronologically thereunder.
  - Prints
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer addressing students, undated (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - Five prints depicting Eric Hoffer, undated (Box-folder 147: 2)
    - Twelve prints depicting Eric Hoffer, undated (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - Four prints depicting Eric Hoffer speaking to a group of military officers, undated (Box-folder 147: 4)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Lili Fabilli Osborne, undated (Box-folder 147: 5)
    - Three prints depicting Eric Hoffer with Erling Roberts, and one print depicting a painting of Eric Hoffer by Erling Roberts, undated (Box-folder 147: 6)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Stacy Cole, undated (Box-folder 147: 7)
    - Four prints depicting a bust of Eric Hoffer sculpted by Jane Rich, undated (Box-folder 147: 8)
    - One reproduction of a photograph of Eric Hoffer by Dan Stroud, undated (Box-folder 147: 9)
    - One print depicting G. Lewis Jones, Brisbane, Australia, undated (Box-folder 147: 10)
    - One print depicting the spine of a book belonging to Eric Hoffer, The Idiot by Fyodor Dostoyevsky, undated (Box-folder 147: 11)
    - Four prints depicting a church complex, undated (Box-folder 147: 12)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer, circa 1950 (Box-folder 147: 13)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1951 (Box-folder 147: 14)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Lili Fabilli Osborne, and one print depicting Eric Hoffer with Steven and Eric Osborne, 1960s (Box-folder 147: 15)
    - Three prints depicting Eric Hoffer working as a longshoreman, San Francisco, 1960s (Box-folder 147: 16)
      Photographs taken by George Knight
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer attending a meeting of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, San Francisco, 1960s (Box-folder 147: 17)
      Photograph taken by George Knight
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer in Golden Gate Park, San Francisco, and one print depicting Eric Hoffer in the studios of KQED Television, San Francisco, 1960s (Box-folder 147: 18)
    - Two proof sheets of photographs depicting Eric Hoffer on the docks in San Francisco, 1963 (Box-folder 147: 19)
    - One print depicting students of Lili Fabilli Osborne, 1963 May (Box-folder 147: 20)
    - Four prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Lewis and Clark College, Portland, Oregon, 1964 (Box-folder 147: 21)
    - One print depicting Ernie Zaugg, South Vietnam, 1966 (Box-folder 147: 22)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer talking to students at the University of California at Berkeley, circa 1966-1967 (Box-folder 147: 23)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Jack Vaughn, Washington, D.C., circa 1967 (Box-folder 147: 24)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, with a dedication to Lili Fabilli Osborne, 1967 (Box-folder 147: 25)
    - One print depicting Col. Joe Cotton, 1967 (Box-folder 147: 26)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer with G. Lewis Jones and Ambassador Allen, Washington, D.C., 1967 October 4 (Box-folder 147: 27)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer, 1967 December (Box-folder 147: 28)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer at the inaugural of Mayor Joseph Alioto, San Francisco, circa 1968 (Box-folder 147: 29)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Hubert Humphrey, 1968 (Box-folder 147: 30)
    - Nine prints depicting Eric Hoffer and Lili Fabilli Osborne during a visit to Texas with E. C. and Mary Louise Rowand, 1968 (Box-folder 147: 31)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with G. Lewis Jones, Washington, D.C., 1968 October 28 (Box-folder 147: 32)
    - Nine prints depicting a bust of Eric Hoffer sculpted by Jonathan Hershfeld, 1970 (Box-folder 147: 33)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Lili Fabilli Osborne, 1970s (Box-folder 147: 34)
    - Six prints depicting Eric Hoffer, 1970s (Box-folder 147: 35)
    - Eleven prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May 30 (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Sixteen prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May 30 (Box-folder 148: 2)
    - Seven prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May 30 (Box-folder 148: 3)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1972 (Box-folder 148: 4)
    - Sixteen prints depicting Eric Hoffer, 1974 (Box-folder 148: 5)
      Photographs taken by Ara Güler
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Helen and Saul Klein, 1974 June 17 (Box-folder 148: 6)
    - One copy of a printed portfolio containing a photograph of Eric Hoffer taken by Ara Güler, 1975 (Box-folder 148: 7)
    - Five prints depicting Eric Hoffer and William Loeb, and one print depicting Eric Hoffer and Lili Fabilli Osborne, 1975 (Box-folder 148: 8)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1975 (Box-folder 148: 9)
    - Three prints depicting Eric Hoffer, circa 1976 (Box-folder 148: 10)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Anne Wiggins, one print depicting Eric Hoffer with E. Bennett Wiggins, and one print depicting Eric Hoffer alone, 1976 January 5 (Box-folder 148: 11)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer, Lili Fabilli Osborne, and Mr. and Mrs. Charles Kitrell, circa 1977 (Box-folder 148: 12)
    - Two prints depicting Eric Hoffer, 1977 December 16 (Box-folder 148: 13)
      Photographs taken by Michael Alexander
    - One print depicting a televised image of Eric Hoffer, 1978 January 18 (Box-folder 148: 14)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1979 (Box-folder 148: 15)